<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="codefornepal.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="codefornepal.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-21T13:10:31-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Code for Nepal</title><subtitle>Community of volunteers helping address Nepal's challenges using civic tech to innovate, organize and advocate digital literacy</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Google data now shows fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the Coronavirus pandemic</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google data now shows fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the Coronavirus pandemic" /><published>2020-05-19T17:48:29-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-19T17:48:29-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2020/05/google-data-now-shows-fewer-people-in-nepal-are-staying-indoors-amid-the-coronavirus-pandemic/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://covid19.gov.np/&quot;&gt;Government of Nepal&lt;/a&gt; has reported over 350 COVID-19 positive cases and two deaths due to this novel coronavirus as of this writing. To prevent the mass spread, Nepal has been under a national lockdown since March 24.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late March, Google released its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/covid19/mobility/&quot;&gt;COVID-19 Community Mobility Report&lt;/a&gt; to help users “understand responses to social distancing guidance related to COVID-19.” Code for Nepal compared Google’s reports from March 29 and May 9 and found fewer people in Nepal are staying indoors amid the coronavirus pandemic. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobility trends for places categorized as “retail and recreation” or places such as restaurants, shopping centers, or movie theatres on March 29 decreased sharply (-78%) compared to February 16. Mobility trends for places categorized as “grocery and pharmacy” or places such as grocery markets, food shops, or pharmacies decreased by 69%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost six weeks later, on May 9, mobility trends to “retail and recreation” have increased by 11% compared to the March 29 trend. And mobility trends for “grocery and pharmacy” have increased by 17%. Similarly, mobility trends for workplaces increased by 37%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For details, check out this chart. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that this data is not representative of all Nepalis. According to Google, “insights in these reports are created with aggregated, anonymized sets of data from users who have turned on Google’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/3118687&quot;&gt;Location History setting&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome your thoughts and comments below.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="General" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="nepal" /><summary type="html">The Government of Nepal has reported over 350 COVID-19 positive cases and two deaths due to this novel coronavirus as of this writing. To prevent the mass spread, Nepal has been under a national lockdown since March 24.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You are a young woman and want to excel in the tech market in Nepal? Apply for this fellowship by March 19</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You are a young woman and want to excel in the tech market in Nepal? Apply for this fellowship by March 19" /><published>2020-03-07T12:13:43-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-07T12:13:43-05:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2020/03/fellowship-by-march-19/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-1024x768.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2518&quot; srcset=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-1024x768.jpg 1024w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-300x225.jpg 300w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019-768x576.jpg 768w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/03/Hawkins_fellows_2019.jpg 1440w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Hawkins Fellows from the class of 2019.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are pleased to announce that applications are open for the 2nd batch of &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/2019/03/hawkins-fellowship/&quot;&gt;Hawkins Fellows&lt;/a&gt;. The objective of the 12-week fellowship program organized by Code for Nepal in partnership with &lt;a href=&quot;https://insightworkshop.io/&quot;&gt;Insight Workshop&lt;/a&gt; is to help increase female talent in the technology job market in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(This is a rolling application process which works on a “first come first served basis”. The sooner you apply, you have a higher chance of being accepted.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;about-the-fellowship-program&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About the fellowship program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hawkins Fellowship by Code for Nepal in partnership with Insight Workshop Academy includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. A twelve-week program at the Insight Workshop Academy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellows will be engaged full-time from Monday to Friday 10 am to 4 pm in the Insight Workshop classes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. A four-week capstone program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the capstone project Fellows can either build from their own ideas and interests or they can be involved in one of the following Code for Nepal projects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asknepal.info/&quot;&gt;AskNepal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitjanakpur.com/&quot;&gt;Visit Janakpur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sangraha.org/&quot;&gt;Sangraha&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;NepalMap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Nepal website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other special projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. A Monetary reward of Nrs 5,000 after the fellow successfully completes the program.&lt;/strong&gt; (The fellowship award including the training, networking and more is worth Nrs 60,000.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning outcomes of the fellowship:&lt;br /&gt;
–&lt;/strong&gt; Leadership and communications skills&lt;br /&gt;
– Access to network with established leaders in the field&lt;br /&gt;
– Project Management: Portfolio-building with Code for Nepal and Insight Workshop**&lt;br /&gt;
–**Technical skills: Open source and web development&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline to Apply:  &lt;/strong&gt;March 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Fellows for April intake:&lt;/strong&gt; 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applicants-must-meet-the-following-criteria-to-apply&quot;&gt;A&lt;strong&gt;pplicants must meet the following criteria to apply:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;able to commit full-time for this Fellowship in Kathmandu&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;background in basic programming&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;identify as female&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;young professional or final year Bachelor’s student&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will call for interviews if you are shortlisted. Three fellows will work alongside the April batch of trainees of Insight Workshop Academy. To know more about the curriculum visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://insightworkshop.io/&quot;&gt;insightworkshop.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fellowship timeline:&lt;/strong&gt; April 6, 2019 to August 30,  2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You only have to fill one application form. Please fill and submit the form below by April 12.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have questions that have not been answered on this page, please ask using the comments section below. Also, here are &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/?s=hawkins+fellowship&quot;&gt;more blog posts&lt;/a&gt; related to Hawkins Fellowship including a few by our Fellows from 2019.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="General" /><category term="scholarships" /><category term="Code for Nepal" /><category term="digital literacy" /><category term="equality" /><category term="fellowship" /><category term="nepal" /><category term="womenintech" /><summary type="html">Hawkins Fellows from the class of 2019.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NepalMap Federal – Explore and understand Nepal using data</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NepalMap Federal – Explore and understand Nepal using data" /><published>2020-02-23T20:41:57-05:00</published><updated>2020-02-23T20:41:57-05:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2020/02/nepalmap-federal-explore-and-understand-nepal-using-data/">&lt;p&gt;Code for Nepal has just launched the federal version of &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;NepalMap&lt;/a&gt;, a web app that puts data about Nepal at your fingertips! Since 2016, this data portal has been the go-to source for many journalists, researchers, entrepreneurs and students; when they are looking for data or data visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the promulgation of 2015 constitution and adoption of federal structure, we see demand for data has increased. Data users have been continuously searching for data from aligned with the new federal structure which includes 753 local bodies, 77 districts and 7 provinces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To meet the demand of users, with the help of generous support of our volunteers, we are happy to launch the federal version of NepalMap – &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;alignleft size-large is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-552x1024.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2506&quot; width=&quot;534&quot; height=&quot;990&quot; srcset=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-552x1024.png 552w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-162x300.png 162w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-768x1424.png 768w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-828x1536.png 828w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap-1105x2048.png 1105w, https://codefornepal.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/nepalmap.png 1425w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 534px) 100vw, 534px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you live in Province 1 or anywhere else in Nepal, you can find out how many people live in your Province or District or Municipality. Or find out what kind of crops or vegetables farmers produce in the area where you live. On this version of NepalMap, demographics, agriculture, educational and household data are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap uses &lt;a href=&quot;http://nationaldata.gov.np/&quot;&gt;National Data Profile&lt;/a&gt;, created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cbs.gov.np/&quot;&gt;Central Bureau of Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, and other official sources, to create user-friendly data visualizations on key demographic issues. You can embed, access or download the data too. You can also compare any two areas side-by-side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code4SA/wazimap&quot;&gt;Wazimap&lt;/a&gt; which is a fork of &lt;a href=&quot;https://censusreporter.org/&quot;&gt;Census Reporter&lt;/a&gt;. Wazimap is built and maintained by &lt;a href=&quot;http://code4sa.org/&quot;&gt;Code for South Africa&lt;/a&gt;. All of these tools are completely open source. You can build &lt;a href=&quot;https://wazimap.readthedocs.org/en/latest/index.html&quot;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; for your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NepalMap is entirely built by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Code4Nepal/nepalmap_federal/graphs/contributors&quot;&gt;volunteers&lt;/a&gt; who are committed to ensuring everyone has access to open data about Nepal. We are looking for volunteers who can help us add more data, and improve NepalMap. If you have the right skills, and would like to help, please complete this &lt;a href=&quot;http://codefornepal.org/en/help/&quot;&gt;form&lt;/a&gt; or you can also directly create issues in our GitHub repo to report the bug. If you would like to access pre-federal data from 2011 Population Census, please check out: &lt;a href=&quot;https://2011.nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://2011.nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code for Nepal is grateful to Clifton McIntosh for his guidance throughout the development process; Amit Chaudhary, Nitesh Rijal, Pratima Kandel, Ishan Dangol for their code contribution and Nirmal Rijal for helping us with data scraping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explore NepalMap Federal – &lt;a href=&quot;https://nepalmap.org/&quot;&gt;https://nepalmap.org/&lt;/a&gt; and feel free to write to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:nepalmapa@codefornepa.org&quot;&gt;nepalmap@codefornepal.org&lt;/a&gt; if you need any further information.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikesh Balami</name></author><category term="Code For Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="NepalMap" /><category term="data" /><category term="Data4Nepal" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="NepalMap" /><category term="NepalMap Federal" /><category term="Open Data" /><summary type="html">Code for Nepal has just launched the federal version of NepalMap, a web app that puts data about Nepal at your fingertips! Since 2016, this data portal has been the go-to source for many journalists, researchers, entrepreneurs and students; when they are looking for data or data visualizations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Volunteers uploaded over 2,000 street-level imagery of Janakpur, a city in Nepal</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Volunteers uploaded over 2,000 street-level imagery of Janakpur, a city in Nepal" /><published>2019-11-23T10:19:47-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-23T10:19:47-05:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/11/volunteers-uploaded-over-2000-street-level-imagery-of-janakpur-a-city-in-nepal/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image is-style-default&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/L7Yvp87lqypDDd10waL9lQzp7Z-Wf3sDyjjZ8KD8JfUBG4ia05zh7zhIgy756jloWD-k7hFElbpkVFIxAB4GLIHHHt8nVWs2InicBBSNHfZaempvuOF80dYXh9FPm4J8nPejKJQU&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[November 3, 2019] Spending holiday by volunteering is fun, especially in this digital world when you can help a group of youth digitize their town. With this aim of mobilizing the local volunteers to map the street of Janakpur on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openstreetmap.org/&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;https://codefornepal.org/&quot;&gt;Code for Nepal&lt;/a&gt; collaborated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.internetmarkettoday.com/&quot;&gt;Internet Market Today&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.appantv.com.np/&quot;&gt;Appan TV&lt;/a&gt; and Smartha Nepal to organize &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/399271194100112&quot;&gt;2019 Digitizing Janakpur&lt;/a&gt; Workshop. It was a followup event of 2018 workshop, where we launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.visitjanakpur.com/?fbclid=IwAR24FeChtVJk4xb1E7hpr_ZZkrzynSNv80_iuOHgjGRHAPpy4EKoM5fomGk&quot;&gt;https://www.visitjanakpur.com/&lt;/a&gt; by mapping businesses of the city, and publishing photos and videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the use of technology has grown, everyone now depends on online search and service. Digital content like blog posts, photos, street views, promotional videos etcetera usually appear in online search results. A town needs to have digital presence and online map so locals and tourists alike navigate the area easily. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Nepal is promoting Visit Nepal 2020 campaign, a platform like Visit Janakpur can be very useful, where the latest information about the city is contributed by local volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The main aim of the 2019 digitizing workshop was: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To use Mapillary, an app, to map different routes of Janakpur key destination.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To teach young people how to become part of Google’s local guides community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To enjoy the hands-on experience of taking 360 photos using Google Street View.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 volunteers gathered at Monsatic Higher Secondary School at 8:30 AM, where they received a welcome orientation from Program Coordinator of Code for Nepal, Sadikshya Karki. She shared the overall program agenda and quickly created a friendly environment within participants through warmup dance. I and Ishan Dongol accompanied her during the introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image is-style-default&quot;&gt;

![](https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ZSxJu8zvnijMZa2lC4Mtd6zGGhbAa1wqMdY0xR3xIoT4ZDvFpVaYlf1rHUHS068Kzz8zxu5_ENvlCNVqmikMv-Qtz5Hkat2y7hQzyGYyGDmNuBTRKRPJj58b6m5G0Gkcn39p5Mg8) &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the short introduction session and breakfast, the participants were asked to download and setup Mapillary accounts for the mapping. Ishan Dongol lead the hands-on session to teach participants how to use Mapilary. The participants then were divided into 3 groups for the field mapping, where they visited different key places of Janakpur to collect street views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image is-style-default&quot;&gt;

![](https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/zPG8jDHEvImkfYGOBoCbkgrfckUrNmf6zhp2RaK1atA3oUdDXDAlDvAI7SKEXhnq2u6N7Uyst73wmr9hUWAA4AOLOtavXkZlnKzXN5kwqHyOoS0ZmPRt2-URCHPuCBnWirrAQ2Z7) &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 3 hours long field visits and short lunch break, the participants went to the office premises of Internet Market Today, where the session on “How Search Works” was conducted by Amit Jha, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Internet Market Today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then led a short session on how to take 360 photos using Google Street View app, where I shared the importance of 360 photos and key tips of taking beautiful photos.&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/i8IL2rN7CBV35o9eUfZLnxUvnVCrwCcjcx9oVy38WDD2h5tvF3L_GTNRUqCf4cnk7V1QuFJVBYGJ1p67xKf-_NCcGp1gcSyysqS_4A4LT6r9OClKlAuVCPDq6FXCed7LdOC8YIdQ&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop was concluded by Navin Shah, Managing Director of Appan TV and Sadikshya Karki, where they encouraged participants to be connected through social media and welcomed their contribution to the Visit Janakpur portal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Outcomes of the Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Participants were able to capture the 21 street view sequences, which consists of 2575+ images of various parts of Janakpur and few 360 photos.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikesh Balami</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="Events" /><category term="General" /><category term="Digital Nepal" /><category term="Digitizing Janakpur" /><category term="Mapillary" /><category term="Visit Janakpur" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chart: Companies in Provinces of Nepal</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chart: Companies in Provinces of Nepal" /><published>2019-10-20T20:21:21-04:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T20:21:21-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/10/chart-companies-in-provinces-of-nepal/">&lt;figure class=&quot;wp-block-embed-flickr aligncenter wp-block-embed is-type-photo is-provider-flickr&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-embed__wrapper&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/bryonlippincott/41800642730/in/photolist-24EnPTi-26FMdLJ-EMfir-EMg5f-29nn4WJ&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/847/41800642730_a64a43ab22_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fruit vendor waiting for customers in Kathmandu, Nepal&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Fruit vendor waiting for customers in Kathmandu, Nepal. By 

[Bryon Lippincott](https://www.flickr.com/photos/bryonlippincott/)  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total number of companies in Nepal is 923,356. Among, them just about half (50.1%) are registered. And on average, companies in Nepal employ less than 4 people. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathmandu, Jhapa, Rupandehi, Morang, and Sunsari are the districts with the highest number of companies in Nepal. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Province 3 has the most companies or establishments, followed by Province 1 and Province 5. Check out the chart below to see how many companies are in each province. &lt;figure&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nada.cbs.gov.np/index.php/catalog/92&quot;&gt;Nepal Economic Census, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>codefornepal</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="General" /><category term="dataviz" /><category term="nepal" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Journey at Insight Workshop through the Hawkins Fellowship</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey at Insight Workshop through the Hawkins Fellowship" /><published>2019-09-19T02:49:33-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-19T02:49:33-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/09/my-journey-at-insight-workshop-through-the-hawkins-fellowship/">&lt;p&gt;One morning I applied for an academy program in Insight Workshop (IW), a Software Company located in Naxal, Kathmandu. The deadline was just the night before. Luckily my application was counted. (Big thanks to my dearest friend Rachana for this). After a rigorous application process I was selected for the program. I also applied for this program from Hawkins Fellowship Program by Code for Nepal. I got selected as a Hawkins fellow from there too. I can’t express in words the feelings that I had that day. I was so excited and nervous about this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone was so welcoming at IW. We were introduced with previous batch’s students, mentors and everyone else there. They shared their experiences and motivated us on the very first day. More than 50% of the trainees were girls; it was a happy feeling. I was around people with the same dreams and passion to become a future Full Stack Developer. Positive vibes were coming from everyone that we were there to learn. It was a different feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month went by so fast. We learned the basics of everything from Html, CSS to Python, Django Framework. We learned how the software development process works in the real IT world. Alongside programming, we also learned problem-solving, research and time management skills. We were given assignments and challenging tasks too to boost our skills. we have to complete them by the deadlines. There were exams too. Every Friday we had guest lectures from industry experts who shared their experiences. I loved how they shared everything with us, making us feel like their own family. They wanted us to grow together and we learned so many things from every person every single day. Every single day was productive. It wasn’t hectic at all; time was feasible, the environment was co-operative and supportive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last four weeks of this academic period, we were assigned a team project based on the concepts which we had learned earlier. Although I entered as a very beginner, in just two weeks of experience and proper guidance, I was able to build a complex web application. This gave me a lot of confidence exponentially raising my passion for software development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back to those three months, these were the most beautiful and exciting days of my life, as my career kickstarted. Currently, I am working at Insight workshop as a Software Engineer Trainee after completing these 3 months of the journey. I am so thankful for Insight Workshop as well as Code for Nepal for seeing potential in me and providing me with this opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sumi Prajapati</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="Digital Literacy" /><category term="General" /><summary type="html">One morning I applied for an academy program in Insight Workshop (IW), a Software Company located in Naxal, Kathmandu. The deadline was just the night before. Luckily my application was counted. (Big thanks to my dearest friend Rachana for this). After a rigorous application process I was selected for the program. I also applied for this program from Hawkins Fellowship Program by Code for Nepal. I got selected as a Hawkins fellow from there too. I can’t express in words the feelings that I had that day. I was so excited and nervous about this journey.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">DataHack 2019- crowdsourcing map data to ease the humanitarian and relief activities</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/07/datahack-2019-crowdsourcing-map-data-to-ease-the-humanitarian-and-relief-activities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DataHack 2019- crowdsourcing map data to ease the humanitarian and relief activities" /><published>2019-07-25T22:48:26-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-25T22:48:26-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/07/datahack-2019-crowdsourcing-map-data-to-ease-the-humanitarian-and-relief-activities</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/07/datahack-2019-crowdsourcing-map-data-to-ease-the-humanitarian-and-relief-activities/">&lt;p&gt;On July 20 and 21, fifteen humanitarian tech enthusiasts came to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/events/2314787745404399/?acontext=%7B%22source%22%3A3%2C%22source_newsfeed_story_type%22%3A%22regular%22%2C%22action_history%22%3A%22%5B%7B%5C%22surface%5C%22%3A%5C%22newsfeed%5C%22%2C%5C%22mechanism%5C%22%3A%5C%22feed_story%5C%22%2C%5C%22extra_data%5C%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D%22%2C%22has_source%22%3Atrue%7D&amp;amp;source=3&amp;amp;source_newsfeed_story_type=regular&amp;amp;action_history=%5B%7B%22surface%22%3A%22newsfeed%22%2C%22mechanism%22%3A%22feed_story%22%2C%22extra_data%22%3A%5B%5D%7D%5D&amp;amp;has_source=1&amp;amp;__tn__=K-R&amp;amp;eid=ARBskecAo9gYSuoCJybITEAm_V_JJbbSplHUM6tX_O-7G5Q6KPV46QB7EaBBsi2GRkXE6OgOKk_paRQE&amp;amp;fref=mentions&amp;amp;__xts__%5B0%5D=68.ARAtEaLuGmhWQpJ4u1hOObfK9ofeOejC6syh6A8qNH4rFa_ACPce1xH4f2P5zvZTc81IVQWBaTFCG2hq5dz141_tFO0dyZ8iukVQb1wsT3P4VPp7Kajhs0pCafgdyFEzScKXC8qC603rkfY4ZPhGhA8_8ciVe7GGpWLQmiKzDAJmWixcoMxV7lTJV_TQeHP9jTTyOMZ8FmIx5vSvTmvroIFhfi49hJ5FViHYgew9pK4Jd7HZMzOCWQF30xFPD0E25XHDME1js5LM5n1mRWqcgqfRRcF2V33U23iJ7oqrfH_FW1gJWDrQCG0qt3_esk5VS5hRq-NkmRk8Alg7gfjRyNGrRw&quot;&gt;DataHack 2019 – Map the districts affected by monsoon in Nepal&lt;/a&gt; at Outside’s office in Jhamsikhel, Lalitpur. The aim of the DataHack was to map the several districts which have been affected by monsoon rains in Nepal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/iDT_hMlrn2ftiovL0uHha6L-VQDnByHzaMQ0o63W2iIaelc6E1FH523-tGpndA72lxqVZeLCzB-IPiYwkAsOajzEwAxuc96zWNjKSj-BrDbjdMeEyIOwum-Qb--MzCJdQw77fp-J&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1, July 20:&lt;/strong&gt; The event Started with participants’ introduction. Our project coordinator Nikesh Balami kicked off the event and introduced &lt;a href=&quot;http://openstreetmap.org/&quot;&gt;OpenStreetMap&lt;/a&gt; (OSM) to the participants and gave a hands-on overview on how to edit the map. He talked about the importance of open mapping and how OSM platform acts as a resource for humanitarian &amp;amp; social causes, giving the users the flexibility to  contribute on their own time as well as have an offline access through the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mapswithme.maps.pro&amp;amp;hl=en&quot;&gt;MAPS.ME&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the overview and some basic discussion, participants started mapping the affected areas. On the first day,, participants contributed to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tasks.klldev.org/contribute?difficulty=ALL&quot;&gt;mapping tasks&lt;/a&gt; created by Kathmandu Living Labs. Although all participants were editing the OSM for the first time, they completely mapped around 38 tasks within 5 hours. Participants mapped the roads, landmarks, residential areas, waterways, etc in the monsoon affected districts. According to Roshan Ghimire, program director at Code for Nepal, learning about the basics and importance of open mapping was crucial. Participants also stopped for a lovely lunch break and a Table Tennis game. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/BAyNlsTcaYG2vETwe-9qWx2h-1f3OvA94Gx-LlTA6Y1y7gLDZ7HS2b-3ociaE0upHGrSL_c0DLauYNMHAqN4NshDE0ZurkCMXQ-auyjIvjSZssB7tzaH3nTW7clZaFnZcDMURl0_&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2, July 21:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;On the second day, participants worked on the mapping of Janakpur city and its surrounding areas on OpenStreetMap. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://tasks.teachosm.org/project/707&quot;&gt;mapping tasks of Janakpur area&lt;/a&gt; was created by Code for Nepal. In between mapping, Nikesh Balami shared how such mapping of disaster prone areas helps ease the humanitarian and relief activities with participants. It helps relief workers and disaster preparedness planners to conduct their programs in these areas more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/VEaEZ8gltRq1b38dgFiuZA6_kA1dgikJs6FXYtYMeawNjDw8VdZPtRc4AUy1VnsJI56m78LSvIjj270tXc8QFTLPGR7YFwL1dITi7bn9I4WjRaY7wE6_-X4oDbCj_e16JwJDacrj&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an informal discussion, the participants gave feedback that the mapping process would be more effective if local people of these disaster prone areas were also involved in the DataHack. On the second day, a total of five participants completely mapped around 30 tasks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many participants have pledged to continue mapping. Being able to remotely contribute to the disaster preparedness work have motivated all the participants. However, just two days of mapping is not enough to complete all tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also contribute by first getting familiar with the OSM platform and then getting started with these tasks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To map flood and landslide prone areas: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tasks.klldev.org/contribute?difficulty=ALL&quot;&gt;https://tasks.klldev.org/contribute?difficulty=ALL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To map Janakpur city &amp;amp; surrounding areas: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tasks.teachosm.org/project/707&quot;&gt;https://tasks.teachosm.org/project/707&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Richa Neupane</name></author><category term="dataviz" /><category term="General" /><summary type="html">On July 20 and 21, fifteen humanitarian tech enthusiasts came to the DataHack 2019 – Map the districts affected by monsoon in Nepal at Outside’s office in Jhamsikhel, Lalitpur. The aim of the DataHack was to map the several districts which have been affected by monsoon rains in Nepal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First month as a Software Engineer Trainee at Insight Workshop</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineer-trainee-at-insight-workshop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First month as a Software Engineer Trainee at Insight Workshop" /><published>2019-05-28T02:34:45-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-28T02:34:45-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineer-trainee-at-insight-workshop</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineer-trainee-at-insight-workshop/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;I applied for this workshop from both Insight website as well as from Code for Nepal &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;fellowship. It was an amazing feeling to know that I had got selected for both. I thought &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;“WOW! I can do this.” I felt more energetic: all I could feel was positive vibes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;From the very first &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;day I was feeling very lucky to be part of this workshop. I took this as an opportunity to learn and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;groom myself in a real office environment. This was the time to implement my theoretical &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;knowledge into practical world. I saw my big picture world i.e future through these tiny steps. I &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;dreamt of being a software engineer since my school days. So this was a starting of my &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;journey.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Talking about my first day at Insight Workshop, everyone was so welcoming.We were &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;introduced with the previous batch of students, mentors and everyone else there. They shared their &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Experiences. There were more than 50% girls; it was a happy feeling. Everyone had the same &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;dreams and these were tech enthusiasts with same passion to learn. There were positive vibes coming from everyone that we should learn and there was a team working environment. It was a different feeling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;The first month went by so fast.We learnt the basics of everything from Html, Css to Django &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;Framework. We learnt how they work in real world and also learned project management basics from tools to practicals.We were assigned assignments and tasks. There were exams. And I even got chocolate and highest marks in the third test. I felt happy. Every Friday we had guest &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;lectures from industry experts who shared their experiences. I loved how they shared everything &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;with us, making us feel like their own family. They want us to grow and we were all motivated and learnt so many things from each and every person every single day. Every day was productive. It wasn’t hectic at all. The time was feasible and the environment was co-operative.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;For the ongoing second month we are divided into team of two members.We have already been assigned &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;projects to implement all our learnings. We have been given time about 4 weeks to complete this &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;project. My only goal for this month is to complete this project with all the hard work I can put i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;n and learn many things each and everyday to make it more productive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-weight: 400;&quot;&gt;I am grateful to Code for Nepal for selecting me as one of the Hawkins Fellow and giving me this opportunity.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Sumi Prajapati</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">I applied for this workshop from both Insight website as well as from Code for Nepal fellowship. It was an amazing feeling to know that I had got selected for both. I thought “WOW! I can do this.” I felt more energetic: all I could feel was positive vibes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First month as a software engineering trainee</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineering-trainee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First month as a software engineering trainee" /><published>2019-05-28T02:28:56-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-28T02:28:56-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineering-trainee</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/05/first-month-as-a-software-engineering-trainee/">&lt;p&gt;After being selected as one of the Hawkins fellow, I searched for Insight workshop’s further background, course curriculum outline and its location to make sure I am going to the right place. In my view, most of the Nepali students get internship experiences where they just come to complete the syllabus of internship or the internship becomes a phase where students begin to lose their zeal in technology. Often, interns do not learn anything due to lack of guidance. I had a slight skepticism whether the workshop would be as promising as it looked. But when I entered Insight Workshop, it was nothing like what I have encountered in the past. It was fairly disparate from any other technology companies in Nepal. It was an ecstatic moment for me when I could see the academy was professionally equipped, provided with well defined resources and supported by highly experienced mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined workshop one week behind the actual schedule which gave me a push to work extra hard to recover my absence. I remember meeting Basna, one of the other Hawkins fellows welcoming me with a sweet gesture and I could feel every other members being cooperative and competent on the first day of workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second week was productive in learning how to use Linux, Source Code maintenance in Git, how to use Skype effectively for communication and how to get access to full stack development tools and technologies. I got familiar with daily practices such as stand up session at sharp 10 AM in the morning with group members, using SCRUM board for personal and project development, mundane update of our progress at the end of day, Friday’s guest lectures and retro discussions on reflecting what went well or not over a week. It was completely a modern reality to perform task by teaming up with other members to solve problems both technical and non-technical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the third and fourth week, we were given Python assignments, Front end designs to clone and do objective tests. I learned to delegate my tasks and I planned to accomplish my objectives by the deadline using Trello and we were provided online learning materials by our instructors.  I don’t like to miss a single day; I love being on time and every moment, I am learning something new. I am not exaggerating about how tough and high yielding our profession is. However, I genuinely sensed my daily six hours at work. Though, nothing comes easy, we have to train ourselves to become auto-didactic, brainstorm ideas, comprehend programming skills, follow stern and unanimous working environment. Last week, we learned to do basic crucial features of web development and I believe that I can develop my very own project with required functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the coming months, I have planned to upgrade my programming skills to take my project to next level, give my foremost at workplace, redraft my professional subjects like CV, LinkedIn profile and build an effective communication and networking environment. Overall, I have attained additional confidence and motivation to work harder in the tech field. I am pursuing this notion in the coming days to complete my purpose of being a Hawkins Fellow and a software engineering trainee.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Seema Thapa</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">After being selected as one of the Hawkins fellow, I searched for Insight workshop’s further background, course curriculum outline and its location to make sure I am going to the right place. In my view, most of the Nepali students get internship experiences where they just come to complete the syllabus of internship or the internship becomes a phase where students begin to lose their zeal in technology. Often, interns do not learn anything due to lack of guidance. I had a slight skepticism whether the workshop would be as promising as it looked. But when I entered Insight Workshop, it was nothing like what I have encountered in the past. It was fairly disparate from any other technology companies in Nepal. It was an ecstatic moment for me when I could see the academy was professionally equipped, provided with well defined resources and supported by highly experienced mentors.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My First Month Experience as a Hawkins Fellow</title><link href="codefornepal.org/2019/05/my-first-month-experience-as-a-hawkins-fellow/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My First Month Experience as a Hawkins Fellow" /><published>2019-05-27T21:18:45-04:00</published><updated>2019-05-27T21:18:45-04:00</updated><id>codefornepal.org/2019/05/my-first-month-experience-as-a-hawkins-fellow</id><content type="html" xml:base="codefornepal.org/2019/05/my-first-month-experience-as-a-hawkins-fellow/">&lt;p&gt;It has already been a month of joining the program as a Hawkins fellow. In these four weeks, I have learnt a lot about the tasks I should be doing as a software engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flash back to the day I first came to IW Academy feeling excited and thinking how the classes and fellow friends would be. I happened to get the confirmation mail of being selected as a Hawkins fellow only on the evening of April 16 when the class had already run for two days. I missed the classes and I had to recover the study I missed. So I reached to IW an hour early to learn what I missed. The friends are so welcoming and it was not hard to learn what I missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classes are running following the syllabus. The environment is so motivating seeing all academy friends eager to learn and committed to the task. The lecturers are always motivating us to work hard in these three months for our better future. Our class starts from 10am sharp and there is stand-up where we in group speak out about our progress to the project manager and the day follows with an hour-long lecture and hands-on practices for the rest of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is no spoon-feeding like we were done in school and college level. We are taught about best practises of using the code, resource sharing and given idea of how hectic job market can be. We are always motivated by our lecturer for self learning. It is important because when we will be doing real job, self learning is necessary because we might have to learn new language for the project. From the first week we were assigned assignments so that we would learn on our own and search and explore new things to complete them. This pushed us to explore new things on our own. We are told that the real job market will be more hectic than how we are feeling now to complete assignments. So regular hands-on practise will make easier. Here we are sat together randomly daily so that we get to know each other, be comfortable and be a good team player. In jobs, we always have to work in team so this is a good practise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel very lucky and thankful to the Code for Nepal for selecting me for this fellowship. It is a good opportunity to apply what I have been learning to volunteer for Code for Nepal and work for utilizing data.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Basna Ranjitkar</name></author><category term="General" /><summary type="html">It has already been a month of joining the program as a Hawkins fellow. In these four weeks, I have learnt a lot about the tasks I should be doing as a software engineer.</summary></entry></feed>